# Vish Dev // vishdev.co@gmail.com

Full-Stack Web Developer with experience in web application development, database administration and data backup and recovery. Currently working as a full-stack software engineer involved in all stages of product development and management in a startup environment.

## **Experience**

#### Full-Stack Software Engineer, New Avenue Inc, July 2017 – Current

- Design and implement web application using Ruby on Rails, Foundation, HTML, CSS, Postgres, JavaScript, jQuery, CoffeeScript, SASS and other software packages to create rich user experiences.
- · Implement and enhance CRUD operations for the application using the MVC (Model View Controller) architecture of Rails framework and conducted code reviews.
- Work in a continuous integration and deployment process on Rackspace cloud.
- · Write back-end programming in Ruby language and Rails framework.
- Work on bug fixes and platform improvements.
- Set up development and staging environments and databases.
- · Git version control rebasing, merging, maintaining a clean history.
- Responsible for upgrading Ruby on Rails, Ruby Gems and 3<sup>rd</sup> party libraries to latest versions.
- Manage product UX/UI ideation, releases and product roadmaps.
- · Evaluate and maintain CMS, internal business tools and web services.

## Ruby on Rails Developer, Gofind Inc, Jan 2017 - July 2017

- Developed website and implemented a user interface using Ruby on Rails, CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery in a collaborative team environment.
- · Involved in deployment and maintaining the application in the cloud using MS Azure's Linux Virtual Machines.
- Involved in handling code reviews and bug fixes.
- · Worked on developing and designing model, view and controller of the application.
- Worked with Devise and Omniauth gems for user authentication and social login.
- Managed code versioning with GitHub.

### Web Application Developer, Independent Contractor, Aug 2014 – Jan 2017

- Developed business and personal websites, e-commerce, social media and e-learning platforms.
- · Consulted with clients on website strategy including functionality and design.
- Gathered requirements from clients and identified key features for making their websites profitable and appealing to visitors.
- Analyzed competitor websites, determined content and communicated progress with clients throughout project timeline.
- · Used the approach of mobile first responsive design for all projects.
- Optimized website performance using latest technologies and industry best practices.

## Backup and Recovery Storage Support Specialist, IBM, Jul 2012 - Aug 2014

- · Created and managed all backup schedules, backup policies that controlled data retention and migration.
- · Coordinated and assisted in problem determination and resolution for backup and restore issues.
- Monitored and tracked backup performance and capacity. Predicted and planned for future capacity requirements.

### **Technical Skills**

**Development:** Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, XML, jQuery, Postgres, Foundation, AJAX, Restful, Git, Bitbucket, GitHub, Heroku, AWS, Azure, Digital Ocean, WordPress, Linux, SQL, Oracle

### Education

**Database, Data Analytics and Web Development,** University of California Santa Cruz **Bachelor in Computer Science with a minor in Economics,** Garhwal University